have you been to isoldi in New York lobster lasagna no I haven't been to
Italy I usually go to two places one is called Norma it's here on 33rd and 3rd
Avenue it's just Sicilian very authentic I love
it the other one which is absolutely the
best pizza in the world it's called sort of below it's very
close to NYU the pizza is just like in Naples and it's like you can't find
anything better on this planet so you know you should go to Seoul below and if
you mention my name you get discount right so yeah I have a special power
yeah Chicago pizza is not Pizza is um pie so if you call it
Chicago pie it's fantastic it's not pizza Napoli pizza is the only pizza
okay all right so what do we talk today about today we talk about something
called the track beggar rapper what are we trying to do today in this lecture so
this is the first lecture where you're gonna help me basically reading with you
along in a paper again such that we can figure out whether things make sense
this is how we educate ourselves in the research world you don't have
necessarily young on your side all the time so you had to read papers and you
had to make sense of what's written there usually I transcribe them again
back with type or ax just for the to fix the main topics in in my mind right and
to commit to time right such that I can check
I can check later what's going on so let's get started so what is this setup
what are we trying to do here so we are trying to design by self learning of a
nonlinear controller to control the steering of a trailer truck while
backing up to a loading dock from an arbitrary initial position only backing
up is allowed so what does this mean what we are trying to do is going to be
learning how to drive a truck which is maybe not that complicated if
you go forward but we are trying to park a track so it just go backward and only
backward so you know if you try to park your car in a parallel parking it's a
little bit complicated perhaps sometimes and not always you can get it done with
one manoeuvre if you have a trailer truck attached to your back it's a mess
we are figuring out this very soon so how does this you know trailer truck
works we have two items we have a cab which is the top right partner so we
have an angle of the cab of the cab with respect to the x-axis and then we have
the coordinates x and y of the of the joint between the cab and the trailer
okay then in the part below we have the trailer and therefore we have like the
X&Y location of the back of the trailer track and then we have the theta trailer
which is telling us what is the angle of this trailer truck with respect to the
x-axis our objective is to drive this guy backwards until the back of the
trailer hits basically the dock location which is represented there with the X
dock and Y dog coordinate moreover we would like to have the theta trailer
which is the angle of the trailer to be 0 such that basically the trailer is
orthogonal to the docking station and basically the rear part or the the rear
yet front and we are earlier part of the is we are back right
I'm speaking English I guess it's correct so there we are part of the
track of the trailer should be parallel to the docking station and as close as
possible to the location of the dock so far make sense right yeah ok all right
so let's read a little bit more for them this paper so we have a state some
state variables there are six and which is not quite I think this is perhaps not
correct what we'll figure this out soon so the state variables are the theta cab
which is the angle of the track then X cab and y car which is the Cartesian
position of the yoke which is the part behind the cab and then you have x + y
trailer which is the position of the rear of the trailer Plus D theta trailer
which is the angle of the trailer okay so basically how it goes is the
following the whole procedure is the following the
track backs up until it hits the dock and then it stops
the goal is to back the trailer to be parallel to the locking to the loading
dock right so the back of so the goal is to have the back side of the trailer to
be parallel of the docking station and then having the x-trail ER and white
trailer the location of the back of the trailer as close as possible to the X
dock and why dog okay are you with me so far
so the initial position is going to be randomly set and then we had to back up
until we saw the objectives to back up until we hit the trailer and the dock
with the back of the trailer and we are exactly like orthogonal okay there are a
few difficulties with this and we're gonna figure out right now what are
these all right so we go CD work key table PTL now we go Conda activate PDL
right now here we have a Jupiter not work so in this case we are going to be
going over these track becquer rapper so something I really like to do in in
Jupiter notebook is who use actually you know the Unicode since we are using
Python 3 we can use unicode right so to write PI there
I just told backslash Pi and I press tab you get pie okay or you
can do alpha beat okay this is not coding this is not books okay so you can
do ugly things like this alright so I just initialize some libraries this is
our setup I initialize some object here we don't care right now and we start by
visualizing this guy here okay and I think I had one zoom a little bit
because you can't see cool okay so now we start the interactive part we'd like
to draw this guy so let me go let's say with zero angle of the steering wheel
and I keep I keep you know executing this alright so this guy here keeps
going and then what's happening here after the next step is that my computer
now is gonna be is complaining and there you go so you get the track is
jackknifed what does it mean the track has is jackknifed you simply broke your
track because you draw into yourself that's very interesting but you can
drive inside yourself with these trucks okay so let me reset the state with
something a bit decent maybe like okay just someone down volunteers what is
going to be now the angle you'd like me to steer the the wheel you can give me
anything from 0 to 45 degrees I think minus 10 so I go minus 10 which is gonna
be turning to the right 10 degrees and I go 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 steps ok off
yeah if I keep going you're gonna be jackknifing soon okay so what should I
do right now someone else or maybe still you class 15 okay let's try plus 15
we go on two three four five six seven eight nine ten hmm okay what next show
you keep going yeah 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 we are gonna be
going off screen maybe alternate plus and minus then you go straight right if
I keep going like this you can see that this track is gonna be going outside
we're gonna be you know going basically game over so you don't have a driving
license so minus 15 okay do you agree all should I go with minus
15 I go with minus 15 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 ok now we cannot drove drive forward
plus 45 we messed up no no I don't think you messed up I think it's still good
zero okay someone said zero let's try with zero not yet okay what do you want
me to do plus 45 okay plus 45 I can keep going but then we are gonna be just oh
yeah one more minus 44 you okay let's go - 45 twice then twice more then I'm
gonna go oh wait no six more sorry well 10 1 2 3 4 5 6 ok
so if I keep going like this we are gonna be going off the screen right so I
think you got the picture right is it twice twice more no it's an older
message that okay the point here is that this stuff it's a bit you know tricky
you can get I you can get like a hand of it and maybe it's gonna be like the
final solution is going to be like something there we go we keep going like
this and then we go in the other direction to rotate something like plus
10 and then it's gonna be killing each other here so plus maybe 25 or maybe
let's see B plus 20 C so we can turn around and
now we should basically undo this thing so if I go like I think plus 40 and
there you go and we can go basically straight steal
something 20 maybe okay and then we can go zero see I've been teaching this
forever so you know I can actually drive this thing okay so there you go yeah
I physicai can there you go see oh my god I'm actually managing to do this we
had to fix a little bit Hong Kong yeah honk the horn I actually had my horn
there so we had to actually oh [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] oh no no okay sorry
okay fine so this actually consider success okay now my computer now is
complaining because there is some lag I should have a turn a little bit before
anyhow the point was that it's not ok done
the point is that it's not quite straightforward to you know to figure
out how to drive this guy because it's highly nonlinear and so we had to figure
out how to implement a high nonlinear system how to invert a high nonlinear
kinematic model basically such that if we had a kinematic model you know how
the vehicle behaves right given an action if you invert the kinematic model
you figure out what action you would like to take in order to you know drive
to a final destination but since we don't know how to do this analytically
or maybe we didn't know and the nighties we can train on your net right and then
we can simply figure out whether we can do some you know we can learn how
whether we can learn how to you know drive backwards okay are you excited are
you interesting to know how we can do this ya know
yes okay let me think so the overall they were all basically
objective here is gonna be that given a initial position in this map here give
an initial position I'd like to know what sequence of actions which is gonna
be basically what sequence of steering angle for the wheels I should apply in
this six dimensional space right so it's not just to D because to D so this this
screen here is gonna be the 2d screen but then you have six values right you
have the X Y of the Cubs X Y of the trailer the two angles so you have a six
dimensional space and then in this six dimensional space you'd like to in fear
like yours or you'd like to yeah you get a network which is telling you for this
specific configuration of the track or the trailer track you should be
outputting this specific value is a regression network
how is going to be outputting you a scalar which is going from minus 45 to
plus 45 I think yeah - yeah yeah I think so I think that's the range for every
position right so our goal is gonna be training a neural net that goes from
points in this six dimensional space to one scalar which is gonna be the scalar
that allows me to you know get a you know a sequence of scalars so but one
scalar at the time such that you would like to drive these track backwards to
the final destination and did I make sense does it make sense
maybe I was confused is he okay alright alright so let's figure out how to get
all this stuff going back to the slides training boom okay training so the
training involves two stages the first one we have to train a network and
you're on that to be an emulator of the truck and trailer kinematics this is how
the paper these people have done right so that's not the only option but it's
what we are going for then a second stage involves training of a neural
network controller to control the emulator which is gonna be basically
doing the task that we were doing right now when we were you know coming up with
a value for this steering angle such that we can reach destination and you
know destination like success is determined by two points due to factors
closeness to the docking station and the orientation of the trader so this is the
overall diagram you can I have a neural net a controller which was me right now
following your suggestions through the chat which is providing you this
steering signal at the time k discrete time interval k then we have a
trailer-truck kinematics which are the equations that allowed me to you know
tell you what is the next configuration of the track which is again we are
giving you the next state given that you provide the previous state inside and
then the steering signal and this Delta here is simply
time delay right such that it tells you that this is the next state and this is
the previous state these are a little bit these are like diagrams from the
electronics like Electrical Engineering diagram so you're going to see because
that's you know there was no computer science back in the days right alright
so a state ok is fed to the controller which provides a steering signal ok
between minus 1 in this case and plus 1 for the track so they kind of use a 10 H
at the output at the time index K each time cycle the truck backs up by a fixed
a small distance yeah so these are the equations for the trailer track with
several tracks you had the location of the X&Y of the cap and then you have
like given that you know the distance the length both of the the cab and also
of the trailers the one the two so on you can estimate what is the you know
the the variation of the angle given the input by the Phi is this negative angle
right because it's on the right-hand side so we have that s is the sine speed
so you can go forward and backward and then Phi is this negative steering angle
positive great positive angles being on the right-hand side right so it's like
sweep swapped and then x and y is the location here back of the of the cab
notice now that basically you have the x and y position of the trailer is
actually determined by the x and y position of the cab and the distance d1
and the theta one okay so before I was selling I was telling you that we had
six values for the state but as you can tell from now we just need four values
right you have the x and y now you have the theta 0 which is do you know the
angle of the cab and then theta 1 that is the angle of the first of the trailer
so you have only four independent values right here these X&Y
of the trailer is completely determined given these other values nevertheless
question aren't these velocities so these are the equation yes so this is
how the the position changes right so these are velocities but so whenever you
have like a state the state in this case is X Y theta 0 theta 1 and then whenever
you'd like to write the equation of the motion
you're gonna write that you know the variation in time so d ya with the
velocity of X velocity over Y and the angular velocity over this guy and the
angular velocity of the other guy are gonna be expressed by these questions in
continuous-time then we're going to be discretized in them since we are using a
computer but this is yeah how we will express you know a dynamic model right
like a model that evolves in time all right so we have the equations let's
figure out now how we train these networks so this is how we train the
network for emulating the track trailer-truck kinematics on the left
hand side we provide a random input which is going to be is going to be like
a random initial value for the for the steering angle and then we provide this
random steering angle to the track dynamics which is gonna telling me given
the previous state what is what is going to be the next state and then on the
bottom part I'm gonna have my first network which is gonna be trained as a
regression regressor and it's going to be trying to minimize the difference
between you know the actual next state and this state that is predicted then
the difference between the prediction and the actual ground truth it's used in
order to and they call these adapt the term they are using the article is adapt
the weights of this network which is basically you know train the network so
how you how do you update the weights of the network the weights of the network
are updated by using this error so question now is
going to be for you what kind of loss function are they
using here since the signal that is used to update these weights it's actually
the difference between the target and the actual prediction
you should be able to tell me now it's actually in the midterm right now it's
one of the question MSE why MSE because if you compute the
derivative of the MSE you get the difference right between the target and
your well you get the the difference between your prediction and the in the
target right and so this div this difference which is here swapped right
is actually used here to change the values in a in our course we perform
gradient descent right so you get the positive Delta the positive you have
prediction - ground truth and that you use that one to compute the partial
derivatives and then you subtract that write the parameter such that you go in
the opposite direction here they actually use the inverted sine sign
right in this prediction - the ground truth is you know factor for you know
adapting which is you know changing these parameters but basically is the
same thing it's a question why are we training the emulator if you already
have a model for the track movement again that's a very good question
because in this case we have a questions and therefore we could actually get a
partial derivatives through these questions but you may not have the
equations right let's say you have a much more complex system you may just
observe right several experts driving this you know complex systems and then
you actually through this sequence of basically trajectory and on this
sequence of location so sequence of states variables you can learn a network
that is able to emulate what is the dynamics of these which is the
kinematics sorry of this system okay that was the answer for Joseph alright
cool so right now let's see how this keeps going oh maybe we should check
them they let me actually switch to the 2d this guy here right so let's actually
start training this stuff right so we we get like towards right and then we're
gonna be running this for loop at the beginning
and so what happens here is gonna be you know we provide some random initial
steering angle and then you know we use the kinematics model to learn what is
the connection between previous state and next state whenever the track goes
outside we just kill it and these keeps going right until we we
have enough points such that we can train these networks to emulate the
track the trailer-truck kinematics again in this case it wouldn't be necessary
because I can we have the equations but let's say we don't have the equations
but we just have you know observations from the real real world then you
actually have to you know you actually had to learn those functions such that
we can differentiate from right we can run gradients ok so if we keep going
like that my computer is gonna crash so right now you can see that this is
taking forever why is taking forever because there is this visualization so
in this case I turn off the visualization such that it doesn't draw
things there and then I can run now for ten thousand times right oh okay and
this happened because I interrupted the other thing right so it's okay how
lovely okay boom and this is quite quick right
because it doesn't have the graphical sorry the rendering okay you're
emulating what players so the emulator let me show you the emulator here is
gonna be trying to learn what is the next state given the previous state
given I provide a specific random steering signal here right so given a
state and given a steering angle I try to learn what is the next state and this
is coming from the ground truth which is this box here okay this is not a
recurrent net right it's just a normal net you have you know an input which is
state plus action and then the output is going to be just action there is no
recurrence right now okay signals are always random at every step
the steering signal it's random this state I collect the whole trajectory
while I input a random steering angle okay a very long question does does is
does this matter that okay it's too long does it matter that the data you're
collecting is a bit different from the human test time action the data you're
collecting changes directions rapidly frequently so there is no it doesn't
there is no time right here my training we haven't talked about training it but
here I'm so this is gonna be a just normal neural net that given a input
state is gonna map it map it to the output state given a specific angle for
the wheels there is no time right so you have one state you have one angle that's
the output no no time right now okay okay so we go here these are my inputs
and the outputs like that I collected over these trajectories so if you check
here I just have the initial I have the initial state I get the state from the
track then I have a Phi which is my you know angle which is going to be
something between random minus 0.5 so minus 5 so from 45 to minus 45 to plus
45 then I have my input so it's gonna be you know the state plus the angle and
then the output is going to be the output of the tracker
track which has step with angle Phi all right so we have this thing here I can
split I can create my network and then I can start
training my network and a zone will keep going until forever but then basically
here we are trying to get a neural net which is simply a couple of layers here
right so linear really linear we start from steering Engle states Terry
steering's so steering size which is 1 plus the state size which is which was
which was 6 right like the x and y and angle for both so x and y and angle for
both the cab and the trailer then you have a number of hidden units which are
gonna be described now in the paper then have very low and then you have the
final inner output MSC and you know STD alright let's go
back to the computer presentation so figure 3 which is the this one shows the
train how to train the emulator so the track the track begs up randomly and the
emulator learns to generate the next position state vector given the present
state vector and the steering signal and you can hear now my computer fan
spinning because it's training ok sorry for the bad audio alright so this is how
we train this system how do you train the controller so this is state
transition flow diagram see represents the controller Sue's another neural net
whereas T represents the truck and trailer emulator so all the truck
kinematics or the trailer emulator either or so how is this thing working
ok so how is now time added to the system so we start with this controller
see this controller see we said provides what the steering angle to the truck or
the truck emulator so the controller provides an angle given that is fed with
the initial state right which in which we can which we can call H of the
k minus one time stamp and if we provide these previous states to the controller
and the track the track we basically get the next state so you can think about
these two guys as you know just one element of a recurrent Network which has
no input or well it could have an input but there is no the input is not
connected right so this is like one of the multiple cells we usually seen in a
recurrent net but there is a different diagram inside so how do we train this
this this is item well you already know the answer right so you get this one
down here we don't have any input on the bottom all right and then you stack
another one you stack on another one and then you keep going until you actually
start from the initial location of the track which is the initial hidden state
or which is basically the initial tracked location and configuration right
and then how on the right hand side so on the right hand side you keep going
right and then whatever until the end where you reach the final point which
final condition can be a few of the following run out of steps jackknife or
third part you hit one of the edges and then I check what is the distance
between your back and the docking station and then I check what is your
angle range or your orientation of the track which should have been horizontal
right okay so those are the answer to the question what is the terminal
conditions there are three terminal conditions jackknifing running out of
steps or hitting an edge and whenever you hit an edge you try to you want to
actually minimize now right what is the distance between the trail that the
docking station and then you want to try to minimize whatever angle you get right
for the trailer cool so figure five training the
controller with backpropagation as you were as you saw before in the previous
diagram we were trying where we were training the emulator we have some seen
something similar with this feedback loop the final state so after you know
you complete this whole trajectory the final state will be ending with some
specific configuration I enforce this final state to be as close as possible
to my target state which means you want to have you know the X trailer as close
as possible to the dog trailer the wide trailer as close as possible to the walk
why doc and then the final angle of the trailer you know horizontals equal to 0
let you make the difference and you send the difference back basically to abduct
these weights but of course it's not just a line the whole thing goes through
it so you use well as usual chain rule right so this actually travels through
all previous TCS right so it goes inside modules the visualization shows that
only the see the controller blocks are updated also proportionally to the final
error which implies an MSc loss again the other thing that we came up with
before cool so the initial position is set at random
the track backs up until it stops final error is just for back propagation and
this is back propagation through time with a variable unrolling period k right
so the weight changes in C the controller are taken as the sum of the
tentative changes what is what is the meaning of this sentence well now you
maybe appreciate why PI torch is accumulating the gradients every time
see the point so in this case you get this gradient coming back from the
future back to the past and then the meaningful thing is gonna be
accumulating all these gradients right because we have reused the same module
multiple time when you go and perform back propagation this back propagation
will sum up things as many times as we went through the you know this module
right that's why PI torch accumulates gradient
whenever you compute backdrop if it would be just you know computing them
and replacing whatever it was before then you just have the gradients of the
oldest iteration high all the welders back the one most back in the past right
instead in this case which what which is written here which say is that the all
the tentative changes are you know some together means you know you accumulate
the gradient over time okay cool finally repeat another initial position
back up until he stops done so the network detail this is you know
architecture diagrams of network architectures back in in the 90s you
start with six values for the state x and Y and theta x and Y and theta for
the two items then you get through these items here that are if they are called
potential potentiometers which are basically variable resistance which are
again representing these variable weights variable weights as in weights
that can be tuned okay so these are tunable weights so weights in a neural
net okay but again this is the symbol for a tunable weight and attainable
resistor you have 24 325 of these guys so from six we go to 25 and then from 25
we go to one which is a steering signal so first affine transformation squashing
second affine transformation squashing and then this guy is gonna be the
emulator so you go from seven which is six of the state plus the steering angle
2:45 so you have a fine transformation squashing and then from these final 45
you have an affine transformation to 6 right which is define and you know next
state cool so that's it right so analogous to a
neural net having a number of affine transformations equal to 4 times the
number of baking up steps so for every time for every trajectory we train a net
which has you know a length that is depending on how many time steps this
specific track took in order to reach you no one's stopping you call it one
stopping what was the world condition right stopping yeah I guess stopping
condition alright so the number of steps varies with the initial position of the
trailer or the track track in the trailer
right so you have you train the core item of this network which has several
steps so have several layers the length of these network changes based on each
specific episode and then we train this stuff with back propagation and each
module is the same module replicated multiple times
therefore the gradients have to be some as you go through right as that's what
PI torch does make sense mmm so these are a few examples you
start with this initial position and then after a few steps the network
manages to reach the destination another one is here they started with the
trailer pointing away from the dock and you can see here how we manage to
circulate around and to get you know back to the correct location in the
final state again is horizont and rain so that's is like it looks almost
horizontal or these on you start orthogonal in a jackknife position right
that's really like being bastards nevertheless the net
can figure out how to solve this you know [ __ ] up configuration and then
this is also you know really annoying but you know the network doesn't
complain be like on your network not just kidding
okay additional resources full working demo it's offered here so in this on
this link I'm gonna be showing you because in the notebook the cold stops
there so here I just show you how you train the emulator and we got like like
an MSc loss down to very very tiny volume like a point like zero point
which is this or there okay you can read this number right and then this is my
value for the for the testing site right so this is going to be 38 micro MSE if
you want to call it here if someone wants an extra grade maybe you can add
the code for training the controller and it's not that trivial because I mean we
cover how to make it work in the in the class but a bit finicky so I just show
you a final version you can even copy from here if you want and I really like
if you can submit would be nice I mean you can get you know a nice reward so
here we can start with a random position and then you can do drive using the
controller let's increase the speed okay and boom another random position okay
it's too easy let's make something a bit you know annoying so trailer let's go
this one let's say 180 degrees and let's have this one zero change angle okay so
this is really annoying and go see buck and
there we go boom okay so here you have the code is training in your browser you
can go also at the bottom of this page and you have this source in github so
you can or even you know encouraged to port this project here which is written
in JavaScript to PI torch it's going to be very a very good exercise for you to
learn we would have actually running notebook which is you know left for as
an exercise for you and you forget additional great I guess alright so that
was it for today class I hope you enjoyed let me see if there are
questions but if we train a policy gradient yeah we don't know about we
don't know about reinforcement learning I don't know anything about
reinforcement learning sorry I'm still confused about the architecture can we
look at the diagram of that again yeah of course here so basically the
controller goes from 6 to 25 and then from 25 to 1 and they use some kind of
finite an age right your activation so 6 to 25 25 to 1 and this is the controller
and instead for the trailer the the trailer-truck emulator we go from 7
which is 6 right the X&Y and and the angle times 2 side is 6 plus 1 7 so from
7 to 45 and then for from from 45 to 6 so this is my predictive model the model
that predicts the future given the past in the actual input action and that's
how I implemented this one here so I have my state size which is 6x and Y and
theta times 2 and steering is 1 just the angle and we say we have 45 units right
so we have 45 units here so we go from steering signal like steering size Plus
stay sighs g72 this 45 then I have real ooh
again the it looks like they use at an age here so okay you can write that H
here and then you have a linear that goes from these 45 to state size which
is 6 which is going to be the next output here right and so there is a
linear output and again this is also something that we just put in the
midterm right I mean I'll give you the answer of the midterm right now
basically so what are you in the emulator actually emulates the way this
villager works the way it works yeah here so emulator training yeah we
haven't I I didn't show you this one you're right so here I just you know get
the length of the training input and I get a random permutation so that I pick
you know at random so I have my file my my angle and the state which are going
to be the seven coordinates is going to be picked from the ice location of these
training inputs and these training inputs are coming down from here
whenever I extract the dry so you have training inputs inputs are gonna be
appending to this list which is this list right input list you append the
file which is the steering angle and then the initial state which comes from
the track so this is my input and then the output is going to be my next the
output step like sorry the output state of the of the track so if you go back
here you get the find the angle and the state are going to be this first item of
this training input okay at the location I'm sorry the ice item of training input
and then you get the next state prediction is going to be the output of
this emulator which has a linear layer as output right cool
then you have the next state which is going to be going to be the output at
the ice location and now you have loss which is the criterion which was an MSc
criterion MSE so you have the MSE between the next
state prediction which is this one and the next state the true next state then
I do basically stochastically in the centrai I clean up the gradient I see so
you're basically training the emulator before you're training the rest of the
next Oh I train the emulator only before so we train two models first model you
train the emulator then whenever the emulator is trained you train the
controller which is driving the emulator but the emulator is not longer train the
emulator is trained only once before then we use the network in order to
train the controller so your first training the emulator and then you're
using the network you trained as emulator kind of control
correct yeah so whenever I'm here I feel I already trained this the trailer and
you later right so to train the emulator as I show you right now the code and
then I can show you also this slide so this is well this was the training of
the emulator the kinematics you have the next state given the previous state and
the angle and then you enforce this emulator to learn to basically do a
regression and you try to copy the output FinFET 5 after you're done when
you're done you actually go and train the controller to train the controller
and you basically have this chain of you know blocks which is controller and
trailer-truck did the track network and then you know you get basically a
trajectory and then you enforce that the final location and the final orientation
of this trajectory they must be you know the docking station and 0 for the angle
and now you run back propagation through this chain of things so it's backdrop
through time in order to adapt the use determine the word adapt in this paper
the weights of the controller such that it managed to map the original initial
run position to this final target position
and orientation configuration let's call it configuration so we start with a
random initial configuration which is corresponding to position and you know
angles and then you enforce that the final output of this you know sequence
of modules is going to be giving you the final the docking station and 0 on the
backside of the track ok so this is two parts training training first the
emulator Phoenix finished that you train the controller in order to follow to
actually reach a specific goal and the number of red boxes here is variable and
it depends on every episode because you don't know how many steps is gonna be
required for you to reach destination in every four given initial condition so
many words I said oh my god does it make sense yes ok very good
next question so somebody did ask this about why we needed to train the
emulator instead of just using the model you know yeah the answer was that not
every time you actually have the questions of the of the of the object
kinematics right so let's say and this is going to be coming up next lesson I
think whenever I'm going to be talking about my own research I'd like to figure
out what is the behavior of other cars when you drive in a highway but I can't
control other cars I have no idea how what is the behavior of other cars right
so the only way I can learn how other cars react to my actions is actually
through observations and therefore we run like you know we we have some
cameras mounted on a 30-story building watching you know looking at the highway
station a highway section and then you basically figure out what is the
interaction between vehicles and therefore we had to learn these four
our model is called predictive model which is figuring out what is going to
be the reaction of other vehicles given to your own actions so in this case yeah
you don't need the emulator but they train these emulators such that it's
more generic you don't need to have differentiable equations again I see
okay one one more question is so when you said the length of this recurrent
network will be variable there was something about having it be like four
times the length of the number of steps or something like that could you go into
that a bit more so here we assume that each length of
each episode is capital K okay so the lower cake lowercase K is the actual
index where you go like zero one two three four five whatever so each episode
has you know whatever capital K number of steps right so capital K is going to
be different for every episode right so each of these two items here this guy
here has to affine transformations and this guy here has to affine
transformations so overall the network that you are
seeing here has four affine transformations times capital K
oh I see okay that's basically one your net right so is a neural net which is
it's not even a recurrent neural net is a is a just a feed-forward neural net
with four times capital K number of affine transformations and now you train
with back prop in order to enforce always the same target right so that's
actually funny to see in this way so you have a neural network which label or
target is going to be always the same but then the network can change lengths
and the input can be different right so you had you have a network you have a
network you input different things you can change the length the height of the
the depth of the network but you always have the same target here right so
usually when you do a regression or classification we have a fixed network
you input different inputs like here and now you have different targets on here
right target or classes if you're doing classification or yeah labels right in
this case you have different inputs the target is always fixed and you have you
know different lengths so you train a network a variable depth network with
variable inputs and a fixed target how cool is that huh
do we enforce like a maximum length of the I I of course of course of course
otherwise you can move why do we need an emulator to train the neural net
emulator is the point of having a neural net emulator to have a differentiable
yeah that's the point right the whole point is to have a differentiable
emulator which is not always the case in case of you know just you had just
observations then you don't have gradients you just have observations and
you want to learn a network that allows you to tell you what is gonna be the
Jacobian as you go back more questions I have a question more
related to just like implementation mmm it seems like for training the
controller we freeze the weights for tea and so but we still need to pass the
gradients through in order to update freely each of the cells that really I
guess would we then like when we define our optimizer we're just essentially
just feeding it the controller parameters but when we called the
backwards it's all still connected to the same network
it's crap so this is gonna be exactly why torch examples what we have seen
last week when we were going through the DC gun so you have like a optimizer hold
on what is it yeah so you're gonna have an optimizer from the one network and I
have an optimizer for the other Network that's it whenever you have the training
you actually have two distinct training in this case when you train a generative
address on your network you have both networks stepping in the same loop but
you can have you know one training thing first you start with the first Network
then you all later below you're gonna have the other you're gonna have the
other network step in there right so you don't you had to optimizers which are
you know adopting if you use this word there from this paper the weights a
different time it's actually two different networks which don't even
train at the same time so you first train the predictive model the former
model finish whenever you finish that you use that as a mean to send back
gradients through the future from the future how do we choose capital K
capital K is the number of iterations that are necessary in order for you to
reach any edge you just go back until you hit something whenever you hit
something that's capital gain so actually whenever we drive forward we
use the kinematic model such that you have a truthful you know we find a
location but then in order to run the gradients backwards you're going to be
using the emulator network so you use the kinematics model to do the forward
pass and you do the backward pass through using the emulator network I
think this can be done better with policy gradient and deep are any model
okay we don't know about RL already for us doesn't make sense I'm
just repeating what the boss says you can try right you can definitely try out
and see whether it works again this stuff was done in the 90s right so
that's yeah it's it's all stuff but it's is always you know I call it pertinent
there you go more questions hi Alfred is about training for controller and
enumerator so the enumerator is trained at each time stab because we are
comparing the predict take the predicted state versus the reason right yeah at
each time step so so we are updating the parameters of any word for every time
step well you can also do a batch if you want but you can do stochastic gradient
this is okay so you can provide like you know sample
and then you update your sample updater and so on right or you can actually you
know step after several after several time steps okay okay and when we hit
okay we just we don't this is not about the emulator right there is no capital K
here oh it's like I'm confused because it's like we we do the training for
enumerative first and then when we hit the terminate state we don't do backdrop
for controller so first you train this network finish done second step you
train the controller next next next alright so you train first the first
network this one with random numbers here with randoms
during signal there is no controller here right yeah okay cool so you first
trained is emulator such that it can replicate these dynamics okay then
second part is gonna be training the controller and the controller is trained
in this manner you provide initial condition you feed forward this initial
condition you basically end up with a trajectory of several you know of each
case until you reach the one of the three final conditions which is you know
jackknifing running running out of steps or you actually hit a wall
if you hit a wall then you run back propagation through this network and
then you do like you're in the center right and now you're doing greatness and
with regards to the controller only see yes yes yes okay okay yeah I got it
thank you okay that's awesome that's it I think and so
you made it until the end of the lesson congratulations alright so how can you
better get an understanding of what we cover today so there are a few things
you can do to keep keep going right comprehension you have some questions
ask them just in the comment section below will answer everyone news if you
follow me on twitter under alpha CN z you can get the latest information as i
post them online update if you subscribe to the channel and turn on the
notification back you will not lose any of the videos i'm posting here
appreciation again if you like this video and the content and everything I
do I would really appreciate if you put a like in the on the video searching
every video has an English transcription which can be searchable and it is you
can find it in the video description below
language SEPA italiano hablas espanol equation putin gua you speak korean
turkish we have now all these translations are now available for you
implying to add more languages is we have volunteers PI torch if you'd like
to have a concrete understanding and digest better this topic I highly
recommend to you to try to train the controller yourself and if he works you
know you can submit a pull request and that's actually the next point and so
that such that we're gonna have now a notebook which will have a running
controller so this again is left to you as an exercise such that you can
actually master this topic okay alright thank you again for listening I see you
next time bye bye